Hassan Sharif Abbud González

Software engineer

+52 (614) 220 9203 • hassanabbud@hotmail.com • Chihuahua, Mexico • Linkedin • itch.io

Profile

Former entrepreneur in the high impact business incubator program NOVA ORION and graduate of the Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey. Experience as a software engineer in the field web and videogame development with a strong dedication for studying and exploring new grounds in software development.

Professional Experience

BLUEWEB SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS

CHIHUAHUA, MEXICO

Web developer and designer

June 2024 - December 2024

- Designed, programmed and deployed various frontend and backend web apps following clean architecture and implementing CRUD operations.
- Developed an automated messaging system for sending phone reminders, integrating a custom API with a relational database and external web applications to streamline the use of the WhatsApp API.
- Employed industry-standard technologies such as Angular, Spring Boot, .NET, and Flutter to develop robust web applications in a coordinated environment.

NEFARIOUS GAME STUDIOS

CHIHUAHUA & MONTERREY, MEXICO

LEAD PROGRAMMER AND GAMEPLAY DESIGNER

August 2019 - November 2023

- Designed and programmed major in-game gameplay systems for the games "The Book of Glory" and "Colors" using Unreal Engine and Unity.
- Structured the object-oriented software architecture in C++ for developing "The Book of Glory" video game.
- Managed projects using agile Scrum methodology to coordinate a 12-person team, ensuring timely delivery and effective project management.
- Facilitated collaborative development and version control with GitHub to streamline and organize projects.

Projects

CANOPUS DATA CAPTURER

JANUARY 2022 - JUNE 2022

COMMISSIONED BY FLEXBPO

 Deployed a web app that generates financial reports using Excel documents, reducing time and effort needed by the company. Utilized Azure, MongoDB, JavaScript, and React tools.

COVYANALIST

March 2021 - June 2021

COMMISSIONED BY PKGLOBAL

• Developed a web form page to study the evolving online shopping patterns in Latin America amid the COVID-19 pandemic. Utilized Bootstrap HTML/CSS, PHP, and MySQL tools.

Education

TECNOLOGICO DE MONTERREY

MONTERREY, MEXICO

B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY,

August 2019 - December 2023

MINOR IN GAME DESIGN.

CUMULATIVE AVERAGE: 94

CHUNG-ANG UNIVERSITY

SEOUL, SOUTH KOREA

EXCHANGE SEMESTER ABROAD,

August 2022 – December 2022

Coursework focused on software design for videogames.

NOVA ORION

CHIHUAHUA, MEXICO

HIGH IMPACT BUSINESS INCUBATION PROGRAM.

Skills & Abilities

Programming: C++, C#, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, MySQL.

Technologies: Visual studio, Unreal Engine, Unity, GitHub, Blender.

Languages: English (Advanced - TOEFL IBT: 93/120), Spanish (Native).

Proficiencies: Software development, software design, gameplay design, level design, project

management, teamwork, leadership, networking.

Professional Certifications

TECNOLOGICO DE MONTERREY

Implementation of computing infrastructure <u>Credential ID 670846b6f80477548fd0ea42</u> Development of computational algorithms <u>Credential ID 670846b5ada87255e5bc7fbb</u> **UDEMY**

Angular: From zero to expert Certificate no. UC-5eeb6698-b43a-4ad0-aecd-de9f50b341b0 Spring Framework 6 & Spring Boot 3 from zero to expert 2024 Certificate No.

UC-fe23fac7-ea9e-4f26-8a45-2f23af90f495